[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Okay, so to handle this situation of having very popular items,
好的 为了处理流行商品问题
we can think about normalizing the the co-occurrence matrix.
我们需要将同现矩阵规格化(标准化 正规化)
And one way in which we can normalize this matrix is with something called Jaccard
我们常使用的矩阵规格化方法是
similarity.
Jaccard相似度
So I wanna mention that this notion of
此处的同现矩阵规格化为问题
normalizing this co-occurrence matrix that we're talking about right now,
非常像我们之前讲过的
is very similar to what we talked about in that clustering and similarity module.
聚类和相似度部分
When we were talking about tf/idf, the Term Frequency Inverse Document Frequency.
我们在讲tf/idf（词频/逆向文件频率）时
Where, there we were looking at documents and we said that really,
曾讲过词频很高的词的作用力会
really common words just swamped out other words that we might have cared about.
盖过我们可能关心的其他词
And so we had this way of using tf/idf to
所以我们才采用tf/idf方法来
renormalize our raw word counts that we were using to represent our document.
规格化代表文档的原词统计
Well, in this case,
在这个案例中这种方法
this is a very similar notion of accounting for a very popular item.
我们可以借鉴来处理流行商品问题
And the way it works is pretty intuitive.
这种方法用起来很直接
We're just gonna count the number of people who purchased some item i and
我们只需要统计有多少人
some item j.
同时购买了i和j
So number, who purchased i and
这是同时购买i和j的人数
j, and that's what our matrix had before.
它的值能在之前的矩阵找到
So those are our raw counts.
这是原来的次数
We're gonna normalize by
我们将用
the number of people who purchased either of these items.
同时购买i和j的人数除以买了i或j的人数
So the number who purchased i or j.
这样就得到规格化之后的次数
And so a simple Venn diagram explains this very clearly.
我们可以画一个简单的维恩图（Venn）来表示
Here's the world of people that purchased item i.
这个圈表示所有买了i的人
And here's the world of people who purchased item j, and
这个圈表示所有买了j的人
Here, in this shaded area, are the people who purchased i and j.
中间划线的区域表示同时买了i和j的人
So what we're gonna do, is we're taking the counts we had before.
那么我们就将划线区域同时买i和j的人数
This is our numerator, this shaded area, purchased i and j.
作为分子
And we're just normalizing by the total area.
除以整个区域
So that's, let me switch colors here to make this a little bit more visible.
我把颜色调得更明显一点
So, circling the whole entire world of unique users that purchased items i or j.
沿着购买了i或j的用户区域边缘画
And that's our denominator.
这就是计算的分母
Okay, so, that's one way in which we can normalize our co-occurrence matrix,
好的 这样我们的共现矩阵就规格化了
and there are other things we can think about like cosine similarity, and
当然我们可以考虑余弦相似度
we'll talk about these other metrics more later in the course.
我们将在随后的部分再 讲一些其他的计算方法
But this method has its own limitations.
这种方法也有一些局限
Here, one issue is the fact that only the current page matters, so
其中一个问题就是它只考虑目前的状态
it only matters that I just bought Sophie the giraffe
在给我做推荐的时候
when we're looking at making recommendations for me.
它只考虑我刚买了玩具Sophie the giraffe
We're not looking at the entire history of things that I've purchased to
却并没有考虑我整个历史购物商品
inform these recommendations.
对推荐的影响
So let's talk about a way in which we can modify our approach to account for
好的 我们可以调整我们的之前的方法使之
my history of purchases.
将我的购物历史考虑进来
Okay, so a really simple approach is just to do a weighted average
一种简单的调整就是给每次我给商品打的分
over the scores I would have placed on the products.
加上一个权重系数
For each item in my purchase history, so
对我购物历史的所有商品都加上
let's go through a concrete example of this.
举例来说
Let's imagine that the only items I ever purchased on Amazon were diapers and milk.
比如我曾在Amazon上买过尿布和牛奶
So now I wanna make recommendations for me, the user that only purchases diapers
现在对我进行推荐
and milk, and what I'm gonna do is, I'm gonna go through every item
我将浏览所有推荐给我的商品
that I might think about recommending, and I'm gonna compute the score as follows.
并对它们进行打分
So let's say I'm looking at whether I wanna recommend the item
假设我正需要
baby wipes to myself.
婴儿纸巾
And in this case,
在这种情况下
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna compute a weighted average over how much I would've
我就会算出收到推荐婴儿纸巾的
recommended baby wipes just based on having purchased diapers before.
权重系数
So that's using exactly the techniques we just talked about.
计算方法我们刚刚讲过
So looking at the row diapers, and
找到尿布列值
looking at how many times people also bought baby wipes.
找出买尿布的人同时买婴儿湿巾的次数
But then I'm also gonna look at the row for milk, and
同样也要找出买牛奶的人同时买
then look at how many times people who bought milk bought baby wipes.
婴儿湿巾的次数 这两个数的平均数就表示
And I'm gonna average these two results to say how much, or how likely it is that
对这两个结果做平均来看看多大可能
I would purchase baby wipes, given this purchase history that I have.
我将会买婴儿湿巾的可能性
Okay, and of course we could do other variance instead of it just the simple
当然我们也可以根据具体情况做一些调整
weighted average I could weight more heavily my recent purchase history to
而不是仅仅简单地计算平均数
account for context and so on.
比如将更近的购买记录权重设大一点
Okay, so then when I want to make the recommendation I just sort
好的 最终只要将加权平均分排序
this weighted average score and recommend the products that have the most weight.
并推荐分数最高的商品就可以了
So very similar to the purchase we talked about before, but
跟之前的购买过程很相似
now we're combining weights based on my purchase history.
只不过现在在购买历史中加上了权重系数
Okay, but this method still has some limitations.
但是这种方法还是有一些缺陷
So for example, it doesn't use contacts, like time of day, at least not directly.
比如没有显著地考虑其他因素 比方说购买发生的时间段
It doesn't use features of the user like my age or gender or
没有考虑用户的特征
anything like that, cuz it's grouping all
比如年龄 性别等等
users together when it's thinking about looking at this co-occurrence matrix.
它只是考虑了所有用户的同现矩阵
And likewise, it doesn't use features of the products.
同样地 它也没有考虑商品的特征
Okay, so everything's just pooled together without any kind of notion
它推荐时考虑的很多东西都跟
of different properties of these products or users to drive these recommendations.
商品的任何特征属性无关
And another big problem that we face here is something called the Cold
面临的另一个大问题是
start problem.
冷启动问题
And this is a really important problem that we face in a lot of different
这是一个很多领域都会遇到的
domains.
大问题
But let's talk about it in this context.
接下来我们细讲一下
So, the Cold start problem is the fact that, let's say we get a new user or
此处当需要考虑一个新商品或者用户
a new product.
我们就会遇到冷启动问题
How do we form recommendations?
这时我们怎么进行推荐呢
Right, I have no observations ever for that product, so
我们没有这个商品的历史购买记录
I have no notion of how often it's been purchased along with something else
不知道它跟其他商品同时被购买的次数
cuz it's never been purchased.
应为它从来没有出现过
And likewise for a user, I've no information about my past purchases.
同样地我们也没有新用户的历史购买记录
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community